LUKE SHAFER

FRONTEND WEB DEVELOPER

CONTACT

614 - 585 - 3382 hello@lukeshafer.com

Columbus, Ohio

SKILLS

Languages

- JavaScript
- TypeScript
- CSS
- SCSS
- PostCSS
- HTML
- Python

Libraries & Frameworks

- React
- Svelte
- SvelteKit
- Strapi
- NextJS

Practices

- Accessibility (A11y)
- Semantic HTML
- Componentization
- Scalable Design

Soft Skills

- Project management
- Team communication
- Customer service
- Patience
- Adaptability

PROFILE

Hi! I'm a web developer with over 5 years of professional experience, focused on accessible, modern, and concise design. I'm experienced in modern front-end web technologies, including React and Svelte, and can quickly learn any stack or technology introduced to me.

EXPERIENCE

Freelance Web Developer | Columbus, Ohio — 2022-Present

- Designed client websites using modern web frameworks and tools
- Collaborated with clients to build the unique site for their business needs

Implementation Specialist, TrueCommerce | Columbus, OH -2021-Present

- Designed software integrations in accordance with customer requirements
- Implemented EDI scripting and XML mapping to meet customer standards

Online Coding Instructor, CodeWizardsHQ | Remote — 2020-2021

- Led curriculum-based 1-hour classes with students in grades 3-12
- Introduced students to HTML, Javascript, Python, and Scratch

Technical Specialist, Apple, Inc | Columbus, Ohio — 2019

- Provided hardware and software support for Apple mobile customers
- Trained and certified in Apple Service Fundamentals

PROJECTS

Do Good Collective, dogoodcollective.org | github.com/lukeshafer/do-good

- Do Good Collective is a mutual aid group I helped form.
- I volunteered to build the website, and worked with one other developer and a handful of artists and designers.
- The front-end is built in SvelteKit, and the back-end is a Strapi CMS server with a PostgreSQL database

Personal Portfolio, lukeshafer.com | github.com/lukeshafer/lukeshafer.com

- <u>lukeshafer.com</u> is my personal portfolio and a place for prospective clients or employers to contact me about my work
- The site is built in SvelteKit and hosted on CloudFlare Pages

You can find more of my projects at <u>lukeshafer.com/work</u>

EDUCATION

Bachelor's, Computer Science, 2018

University of Cincinnati, Cincinnati, Ohio